{"Topic": "Skeletal System", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Questions : Bones and Joints.", "op1": "33", "op2": "32", "op3": "22", "op4": "26", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Number of vertebrae in human is", "op1": "stapes", "op2": "humerus", "op3": "ulna", "op4": "femur", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The longest bone in the human body is", "op1": "Bony matter", "op2": "White fibrous cartilage", "op3": "Hyaline cartilage", "op4": "Aerolar tissue", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following connects the Sternum to the ribs?", "op1": "Hairline fracture", "op2": "Pulling of the ligament", "op3": "Greenstick fracture", "op4": "Muscle tear", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is generally called a Sprain?", "op1": "10", "op2": "8", "op3": "4", "op4": "2", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The number of saddle joints in human body is", "op1": "30", "op2": "24", "op3": "26", "op4": "60", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the total number of bones found in right upper limb?", "op1": "42", "op2": "32", "op3": "12", "op4": "22", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "How many bones are present in human skull?", "op1": "58", "op2": "56", "op3": "60", "op4": "54", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the total number of bones in the both the lower limbs of a man?", "op1": "3 pairs", "op2": "2 pairs", "op3": "4 pairs", "op4": "12 pairs", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the number of floating ribs in humans?", "op1": "Saddle joint", "op2": "Gliding joint", "op3": "Pivot joint", "op4": "Hinge joint", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What type of joint is found in wrist?", "op1": "Ankle joint", "op2": "Elbow joint", "op3": "Shoulder joint", "op4": "Thumb joint", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which  of the following is a Ball and Socket joint", "op1": "Orthopaedics", "op2": "Odinthology", "op3": "Gerontology", "op4": "Oncology", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The branch of medical science which deals with the prevention or correction of the musculoskeletal system is called", "op1": "Sternum", "op2": "Clavicle", "op3": "Pelvic bone", "op4": "Hyoid bone", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a part of the pectoral girdle?", "op1": "Osteocytes", "op2": "Osteoblasts", "op3": "Osteoclasts", "op4": "Osteons", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What are bone forming cells called?", "op1": "72", "op2": "48", "op3": "126", "op4": "80", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many bones does the axial skeleton have?", "op1": "Scapula", "op2": "Patella", "op3": "Sternum", "op4": "Tibia", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is sesamoid bone?", "op1": "Hips", "op2": "Chest", "op3": "Neck", "op4": "Knee", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which place in the human body would you find the hyoid bone?", "op1": "Thoracic vertebrae", "op2": "Cervical vertebrae", "op3": "Coccygeal vertebrae", "op4": "Lumbar vertebrae"}, {"Question": "Which of the following is NOT a part of the axial skeleton?", "op1": "Sternum", "op2": "Vertebral column", "op3": "Scapula", "op4": "Skull", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following bones of the skull is movable?", "op1": "Nasal bone", "op2": "Temporal bone", "op3": "Maxilla", "op4": "Mandible", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following bones is associated with hip replacement surgery?", "op1": "Patella", "op2": "Sternum", "op3": "Femur", "op4": "Fibula", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The total number of facial bones is", "op1": "12", "op2": "16", "op3": "14", "op4": "18", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not associated with the bones in human body?", "op1": "Production of red blood cells", "op2": "Control of blood sugar", "op3": "Protection of internal organs", "op4": "Storage of minerals", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following joints can move in only direction?", "op1": "Hinge joint", "op2": "Ball and Socket joint", "op3": "Gliding joint", "op4": "Pivot joint", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The bones of cranium are joined by", "op1": "Ligaments", "op2": "Tendons", "op3": "Sutures", "op4": "Cartilages", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In the human body, the number of cervical vertebrae is -", "op1": "5", "op2": "7", "op3": "8", "op4": "12", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The other name for knee cap is -", "op1": "clavicle", "op2": "patella", "op3": "radius", "op4": "femur", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "About how many bones does a newborn baby have?", "op1": "206", "op2": "270", "op3": "225", "op4": "190", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The number of bones in the human body system is :", "op1": "306", "op2": "206", "op3": "260", "op4": "370", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "An example of ball and socket joint in the human body can be found in the \u2013", "op1": "Shoulder", "op2": "Knees", "op3": "Ankles", "op4": "Elbow", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which bone is not attached to any other bone in the human body?", "op1": "Stapes", "op2": "Patella", "op3": "Hyoid", "op4": "Scapula", "Answer": 3}]}